Hi.
My name is Derek Tarnow, I've been playing guitar for twelve years and I teach and perform.
In this clip, I'm going to talk about selecting guitar strings.
The first thing to decide when selecting guitar strings is, you know, what guitar you're selecting guitar strings for.
I got out a couple of different kinds of guitars here.
Just to show that, you know, hey, there are different kinds of guitars and they all need different strings.
What I'm holding is a classic guitar.
It needs a nylon strings.
A safe bet, when you're buying strings for just about any guitar is D'Addario.
They make at you know, least decent strings to the best strings for whatever the guitar you're going to restring.
What I have on here now are actually the D'Addario Pro-Arte Classical Guitar Strings.
Because it's a classical guitar.
Over here I have my strap for my electrical guitar.
On this guitar I like to, to just play just the regular D'Addario strings for electric guitars.
Over here, I have a hollow body.
On this guitar, I like to use Flat Wounds, but that's total a preference thing.
Flat Wound strings on most guitars like, like your strats or your acoustic guitars you have Round Wound Strings.
On the Flat Wound Strings, the wrapping or the around the strings is flattened to reduce the fret noise.
But again, on this guitar, I just have the D'Addario chromes which is just their flat wound series of strings.
On my acoustic, I don't play acoustic very often, so I don't.
I'm not too picky about strings on that.
I think for right now actually just Martin Strings on it because it's a Martin Guitar.
It doesn't really matter.
You don't have to match your guitar with your strings at all.
In fact, it's usually not a good idea.
Also an important thing to consider when you're choosing guitar strings is, maybe you're playing ability.
If you are a beginning student, you might want to start with a lighter gage string.
If you're younger, maybe some eights.
If you're a little older like, like by older like late middle school, really high school, get some nine gage strings.
Your hands can usually handle it.
Also, what kind of style you're playing.
Bluesier guitar players like to play on a little heavier strings then metal players.
Metal players on really light gage strings.
Because they get that really shrieky, streaking sound that they go for.
Anyway, if you have any questions about guitar strings.
Generally when you go to a guitar music shop, there would be someone there that would know what they're talking about, to help you out and to help you choose a set of strings that would get you by.
Also, don't be afraid to experiment and try new strings because that's really the only way that you're going to find out what strings you like or don't like and why.
And that is an important thing to know.